Jesse Mwangi

jessejzee@gmail.com

(+358) 413104557

(+358) 413104557

• Helsinki, Finland

in linkedin.com/in/jesse-mwangi

github.com/Jessemwangi

PROFILE

I have a strong foundation in .Net C# & VB, React.js, Node.js, and the fundamentals of TypeScript. Additionally, I have extensive knowledge of SQL Server and SQL reporting server, experience with DevOps and entry-level in cloud computing, Agile development practices, and project management. In my previous employment, I successfully delivered two big projects, a recruitment system and with my colleague, a revenue collection system, that integrates with banks and mobile money (MPESA)

EXPERIENCE

System Developer

County Government Of Uasin Gishu

😇 Sep 2016 - Nov 2022

Uasingishu.go.ke - http://uasingishu.go.ke/------Managed to lead a team in the development and deployment of the Revenue collection
system, my main area of the task was back-end, working with SQL server to create store procedures, triggers, and queries, also SSRS
reports Diagnose application failures and develop procedures to correct problems and make modifications to user procedures, user data
entry instructions, user training programs, and data files and structures Create and manage test and development environments to allow
system improvements to be made with the minimum impact on services. Design, script, code, test, and document the development of
custom software, I developed a jobs and recruitment system using .Net framework, VB, and SQL server Prepare and submit appropriate
reports as and when required

Content And Design Specialist

iii Jan 2014 - Sep 2016

County Government Of Uasin Gishu

Created County integrated platform using WordPress and media monitoring website using .NET VB and SQL 2012 as the database server
Create or curate relevant, compelling, engaging social media content to reach our clients' ideal customers Ensure that the county website
design is appealing, easy to access resources and information, and that contents are up to date Work with clients to obtain video,
photographs, and text testimonials to utilize as content for the website and social media.

Ict Officer Dec 2010 - Apr 2012

Nanotech It Technologies

Networking, hardware, and junior software technician. Software and website development, installation, and support (VB.NET, VB 6.0,
Joomla, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, basic Php, essential SQL, intro C++) Switches and routers configuration and Computer networking using
PAP, CHAP, PPP and DLCI.

Intern Intern

Coca-cola

ICT Intern; task with computer general ICT support, computer repair, and maintenance, troubleshooting organization ERP and content
management of their website,

+358 413 104 557 jessejzee@gmail.com

EDUCATION		
FullStack Developer		== 2022
Business College		
FullStack Developer from Helsinki		
Advanced Certificate		<u>iii</u> 2017
Aptech College		
Advanced Certificate from Delhi		
Bachelor of Informatics, IT		<u>iii</u> 2015
Mount Kenya University		
Bachelor of Informatics from Nairobi		
Cisco Certified Network Associate		<u>iii</u> 2010
Kenyatta University		
Cisco Certified Network Associate from Nairobi		
Advance Diploma, Computer, System Engineer	ing, Hardware Maintenance	<u>iii</u> 2009
Elgon View College		
Advance Diploma in computer engineering Advance Diploma	from Eldoret	
LANGUAGES		
English	Fluent	

OTHER SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

BootCamp Certificate for Backend Web Development using JavaScript, Node.js, and Express, web server configuration (Apache and IIS)

+358 413 104 557 jessejzee@gmail.com